CANDRA S. FRIED

UX/UI ENGINEER, DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

ADDRESS

E-MAIL

WEB

PHONE

DESOTO, TX

CANDRACODES@GMAIL.COM

CANDRACODES.COM

214.417.0503

MMAR

UX/UI Specialist with career experience spanning over 14 years. Routine tasks include prototyping web interfaces with information architecture, writing HTML, CSS and JavaScript to create user-friendly designs and easy-to-read code. Provides graphic design aid (i.e. wireframes for conceptual design, brochures, training guides, logos, icon creation and more). Serving as a liaison between IT and marketing, being held accountable for design and development decisions and mentoring junior designers and developers. Constantly learning new web languages and staying abreast of new design and development trends. I make things functional and pretty.

EDUCATION

MASTERS INFORMATION SCIENCE Penn State Great Valley June 2014

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATION LaSalle University May 2011

BFA ILLUSTRATION/GRAPHIC DESIGN Moore College of Art & Design May 2006

DEVELOPMENT

HTML/HTML5

CSS/ LESS/ SASS

BOOTSTRAP

BULMA

JAVASCRIPT/ TYPESCRIPT

ANGULAR JS/ ANGULAR

JQUERY

NPM

NODE.JS

BOWER

GRUNT

PHP/MYSQL

AMCHARTS.JS

CHARTS.JS MORRIS.JS

EXPRESS.JS

SEMANTIC UI

D3.JS

FONT AWESOME

MATERIAL.IO

JSON/ AJAX

JADE/PUG

DATATABLES VISUAL STUDIO

VISUAL BASIC

GIT/GITHUB WORDPRESS

AGILE/ KANBAN

JIRA

CLOUD FOUNDRY

ATLASSIAN/ CONFLUENCE

SFO

ADA COMPLIANCE

DESIGN/MARKETING

ADOBE CC:

* PHOTOSHOP

* ILLUSTRATOR

* INDESIGN

* ACROBRAT

* CAPTIVATE

MICROSOFT OFFICE:

* WORD

* EXCEL

* POWERPOINT

* OUTLOOK

* SHAREPOINT

WIREFRAMING TOOLS:

* BALSAMIQ

* AXURE

* VISIO

* DRAW.IO

* INVISION

CREATIVE DIRECTION

WIKI PAGE CREATION

USER STORY CREATION

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

TECHNICAL WRITING

GOOGLE ANALYTICS

REPORTING

ILLUSTRATION

ADVERTISING

INFOGRAPHICS

CASE STUDIES

FOCUS GROUP LEAD

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE CONSULTING

www.CandraCodes.com / Remote / On-going since 2002

In addition to working fulltime for my current employer, I take on freelance projects (as time permits). Projects range from art, design, development, branding/identity, and project planning (so long as they are not a conflict with my employer). Clientele includes both individuals as well as corporate companies. Recent notable freelance clientele includes: Singer/Songwriter Jill Scott, The Blues Babe Foundation, Customized Energy Solutions, Blu'Phier Publications, Grammy award-winning band Snarky Puppy, The Flaming Skillet Catering, Townview Realtors, music producer Antone Amalbert, Singer/Songwriter Brayla and many more. I also create handmade original arts & crafts which are available in my Etsy store: www.etsy.com/shop/FriedCookieCreations.

UX/UI ENGINEER

ReturnLogic / Remote / December 2019 - Current

Currently serving as UX/UI lead for the SAAS returns management startup. Routine responsibilities include wireframe creation using Axure, front-end development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS (for our legacy system — Angular 8 for our newer application) and establishing customer trust through focus group discussions. I lead a small team composed of junior designers, developers and interns. Since the company is still in its infancy, I wear many hats and responsibilities rotate from design and development work, to mentorship, research as well as administrative duties. I take ownership of all current design decisions and talk frequently to stakeholders to defend those decisions. I'm passionate about the work I've done to assist in our application's user interface and human-centered experience, and I work diligently to deliver results.

CYBERSECURITY AUTOMATION ENGINEER/ SENIOR DESIGNER

Comcast / West Chester, PA / June 2017 - December 2019

This position began as a contract position (via Xavient) for Senior Web Designer. I was later promoted to full time staff as the Cybersecurity Automation Engineer. In this role, I acted as lead design/developer for the Security Development & Analytics Team. My focus was centered on supporting all automation and development efforts within the Cybersecurity organization. I applied and integrated emerging technology trends to new and existing systems. I was responsible for writing high quality source code to complete applications within deadlines. My project involvement included: idea/concept phase with stakeholders, wireframing/prototyping, UI architecture management, development using HTML/CSS/Angular (Javascript/Typescript), RESTful API calls and integration, testing, debugging and hosting applications (Github and Cloud Foundry), innovation and mentorship. Additional responsibilities often included designing logos across divisions, marketing materials, creation of on-boarding training guides for all new engineers and all creative materials. I also had the honor of being a 2019 mentee in Comcast's CLEAR (Comcast Leadership Engineering Achievements & Relationships) Mentorship program.

UIX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

GeoDecisions / Philadelphia, PA / Aug. 2016 - May 2017

UIX Designer and Developer working from both the Philadelphia and Harrisburg offices. I served as a supportive role for enterprise solutions development, leveraging responsive design techniques in both Agile and Waterfall environments. A player on the software development team working on client requirements. Design lead for creating user interfaces for web applications while conducting usability (A/B) testing. Development of design using JavaScript and mocking frameworks (i.e. Balsamiq, Axure, Visual Studio and the Adobe Creative Suite). Geospatial UIX Consultant for Pennsylvania Department of Transportation (PENNDOT) as a representative of GeoDecisions and Gannett Fleming.

WEB CONTENT DEVELOPER

Affiliated Distributors (AD) / Wayne, PA / Sept. 2014 - Aug. 2016

Routine responsibilities for this role included creating, developing, and maintaining the company's web presence through HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the use of Content Management Systems (CMS) such as Drupal and Vignette. I tracked and reported all site metrics with B.I. tools such as Google Analytics. I monitored and adjusted content in support of SEO targets. I was solely responsible for incoming web requests and performing quality assurance testing for several projects. I provided creative direction and consultation for all current and future online efforts in support of ecommerce customer needs, as well as IT support for development of new divisions, mergers and acquisitions. Finally, I provided user experience expertise, supplying storyboarding, site-mapping, wireframing, and prototyping for both internal and customer-facing projects.

EXPERIENCE

WEB DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

Progressive Business Publications / Malvern, PA / Dec. 2011 - Sept. 2014

I provided creative direction for designers in all sub-divisions. I worked primarily with WordPress theme creation, updates and relevant PHP coding. I was Involved in the full life cycle of web projects, severing as a bridge between the Marketing and IT Department. I executed marketing needs from concept development to creative deliverables. Creative deliverables included (but were not limited to): graphic and web design, web banners, advertisements, infographics, PowerPoint presentations, flash projects, widgets & logo creation, software development, landing pages, email blasts, plugins, storyboarding and researching.

SENIOR GRAPHIC & WEB DESIGNER

L.F. Driscoll Co., LLC / Bala Cynwyd, PA / Oct. 2006 - Dec. 2011

This position began as Graphic Designer and ended as Senior Graphic & Web Designer. Routine responsibilities included frontend web development, some backend work via PHP, working alongside architects and project managers to coordinate logistics plans, building information modeling (BIM), marketing materials (i.e. proposals, RFPs, RFQs, brochures, branding, graphs, charts, tradeshow materials, advertising, banner creation and more).

MULTIMEDIA INSTRUCTOR

W.B. Saul High School / Philadelphia, PA / Sept. 2008 – June 2010

Part-time instructor for the "Scholarship in Training" after-school program. I taught grades 9 – 12 multiple facets of traditional art, graphic and web design.

AFFILIATIONS & AWARDS

2019 COMCAST C.L.E.A.R. MENTORSHIP PROGRAM
WOMEN IN CABLE TELECOMMUNICATIONS (WICT)
COMCAST BENGINEERS (BLACK ENGINEERS)
TECH WOMEN PHILLY
WOMEN WHO CODE (DFW/PHILADELPHIA)
2014 RAINMAKER AWARD FOR INNOVATION